# Diego Johnson Ludeña

Software Engineer | Full-Stack Developer

Lima, Peru 1 +51 961 460 601

diegojohnson46@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/diegojohnsonl in

Software Engineer Bachelor with 2 years of real-work experience. I'm interested in web development, cybersecurity, and backend development. My academic path has been defined by a solid foundation in C++, Python and Typescript developed through building CLI tools, games, web applications and AI models.

#### Skills

- FRONT-END DEVELOPMENT | React Next.js TypeScript Chakra UI Flutter Angular Bootstrap HTML-CSS
- BACK-END DEVELOPMENT | Java Spring Boot Scala Node.js NestJS Golang
- SOFT SKILLS | Communication Critical Thinking Leadership
- TOOLS | Git Docker SQL/NoSQL
- LANGUAGES | Spanish, native English, advanced

### **Experience**

AUG 2023 - JAN 2024

#### Front-End Developer / The Meteor Company, Lima, Peru

- Collaborated with an international team to implement new client requirements.
- Used TradingView charts to implement cryptocurrencies pairs trading component.
- Developed Deposit, Internal Transfer and Withdraw components for customers' custodied wallets.
- Managed the web application headless Content Management System.

MARCH 2022 - MARCH 2023

# Full-Stack Software Developer / Remote Technology Inc, Lima, Peru

- Decoupled the monolithic backend into multiple microservices.
- Implemented a centralized logging system for the backend microservices.
- Configured the production server's environment, domains, and CI/CD to host microservices.
- Refactored mobile app from using Java to Kotlin and implemented a MVVM architecture.
- Maintained and implemented new features in both the mobile app and backend microservices.

### Education2017 - 2023

Software Engineering Bachelor / Peruvian University of Applied Sciences, Lima, Perú

## **Certificates**

AUG 2023

The Complete 2023 Web Development Bootcamp / Dr. Angela Yu, Udemy

JUN 2023

IBM Cybersecurity Analyst / IBM, Coursera

OCT 2022

The Complete Flutter Development Bootcamp with Dart / Dr. Angela Yu, Udemy